

QA ENGINEER

Portfolio:

https://github.com/maksimenkoveronika

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1za MO7IQZAgJBmCj9 wdrcHOE-ltkqAEu? usp=sharing

EDUCATION

√ 2022

· <u>April - July</u>

Author's course by Vadim Ksendzov

√ 2021:

· <u>November - December</u> Belhard Academy (Advanced software testing course);

· <u>September - October</u> Belhard Academy (Basic software testing course);

✓ 2014 - 2018 GSTU (Software engineer);

✓ 2010 - 2014 BGAEC (Technicist software).

TRAINING

- Books (Svyatoslav Kulikov, Roman Savin);
- Online courses (Rusau, Marshal)
- Stepik Interactive SQL trainer;
- Yandex testing course. Workshop;
- Jira course:
- Python Generation (Fundamentals) course.

LANGUAGE

Russian - native

English - pre-intermediate

VERONIKA MAKSIMENKO

CONTACT

- P: +995 591062044 (Tbilisi)
- E: maksimenko.veronika95@gmail.com
- L: linkedin.com/in/veronika-maksimenko

About me

I have always been interested in the software development process. I like to check software products for operability, as well as improve their quality.

This is creative work to improve the user experience of the product. At the moment I am taking a course with Vadim Ksendzov, gaining practical skills, and also being a mentor of the course.

HARD SKILLS

- Used tools for testing in practice: Fiddler, Charles;
- I know how to work with DevTools;
- I know how to work with Postman (creating collections, using snippets);
- Worked with Rest, API web service (post, get, delete requests);
- I can write SQL queries (group by, having, join, order by);
- Can write scripts for load testing (JMeter);
- Used Android Studio in mobile testing (logcat);
- I have theoretical knowledge of computer networks;
- Can work with commands Linux (Git Bash);
- Used Git in practice.
- Understand the whole process of software testing and development;
- I know the types and levels of testing, I can apply in practice;
- Studied testing methodologies, understand the differences;
- I know how to apply test design techniques in practice;
- Create and use test documentation (checklists, test cases);
- Studied the features of writing a test plan;
- Can write defect reports;
- Tested a web form (input fields, registration form);
- Studied the features of mobile testing (emulators, simulators, farms);

SOFT SKILLS

- Continuous learning, self-development;
- Ability to work both in a team and individually;
- Easy adaptation, high learning ability;
- Multitasking and responsibility;
- Ability to prioritize;
- Proper wording of questions;
- I am able to resolve conflict situations
- Communication and friendliness.

EXPERIENCE

April 2022 — current Mentor of QA course

I am taking a course of Vadim Ksendzov, and I am a mentor in my group. On the course I get real practice and improve my skills.

During the course, I modernized the collection of useful links into one large table with resources on various topics. On an ongoing basis, I am engaged in consultations on issues that have arisen during training. I check my homework on a daily basis.

I also have a separate group of people where I not only help students study the course material, but also check homework, motivate, support, and share my knowledge.

March 2022 — May 2022 QA Engineer

- Work with the version control system;
- Determination of requirements for tests;
- Carrying out functional testing;
- Development of test documents, including test plan;
- Preparation of test data in accordance with the work assignment;
- Testing of accompanying documentation;
- Definition and description of test cases, including development of autotests;
- Registration of defects in the control system;
- Analysis of test results;
- Review fixed defects in order of their priority.